No, there's this
amazing study that showed that let's say
the age of retirement 65. If you're 63
or 64 and you are unemployed, your
quality of life is very bad. People who
are unemployed generally feel very bad
about themselves, sleep poorly, they
tend to get depressed. Uh it's very very
bad for your psychology and your
well-being to be unemployed. Somebody
who's unemployed at 64, when they turn
65, they're not unemployed anymore.
They're retired now. The moment that you
switch from unemployed to retired,
suddenly people are way happier. Now,
why is that?
There's always been this thinking, this
idea that people got richer they were
going to work less and there was going
to be more time for leisure, [music]
more time for play. What we have learned
over time is that that's not actually
what human beings want to do. The richer
that they get, the more that they want
to work. People actually really want to
be valuable. It's a deep human need.
By 2010, we already had Facebook, we had
LinkedIn, we had Snapchat, we had almost
all these companies already existed by
2010. So, the story from 2010 to 2027
was just eating everything. Growing to
dominate the world.
And I suspect that that's the stage that
we're in with crypto. But, the scale is
only going to get bigger and bigger.
The internet era where you hold the good
company, the right company, you're going
to make it. In crypto, we have equity
and token. Where does the value go? All
of the stock market for crypto is worth
less than half of there.
Okay, if you were starting [music]
your career today, would you pick
This is a stupid mentality. This is a
stupid mentality. Your problem is that
you are so flighty and [music] you just
constantly change your mind.
That's ridiculous.
I'm really happy to be joined by Haseeb
Qureshi. He is the managing partner of
Dragonfly. You went from professional
poker player to Silicon Valley software
engineer and to one of the most
influential people in crypto. Well,
thank you. That's uh it's very high
praise. I don't know if I can live up to
that, but thank you. You've seen three
very different stages and competitive
environment, uh poker, Silicon Valley,
and crypto. Which one taught you the
most about how the world really works?
How the world works? Um
It's a good question. I'd say crypto
investing definitely taught me the most
how the world works.
Uh crypto is is unique because
it's an industry that has touched almost
everything at some point. Sometimes it's
touched them in a way that got rejected.
So, you know, you think about um
you know, things like gaming.
Uh I had to learn a lot about the gaming
industry in 2021, 2022 when crypto was
like, "Oh, we're going to disrupt all
the gaming industry and all the future
of games are going to be on
blockchains." I didn't know, you know,
I'd played video games, I didn't know
about the video game industry. So, I had
to learn a lot about that. Um or people
talking about, "Oh, crypto's going to
replace supply chains. It's going to
totally disrupt the way that IoT works
or this industry or that industry." And
so, being a crypto investor, you kind of
have to learn about almost everything.
Um you have to learn how the law works
because, of course, you know, crypto is
constantly under the crosshairs of the
law. You have to learn how bankruptcy
works. You have to learn how FDIC works.
Um
I've learned so many things over my
journey as a crypto investor that I
think in most of the domains you just
don't have to learn. You know, most
things are pretty contained and myopic.
But, crypto touches geopolitics, it
touches, you know, law, it touches
philosophy, it touches economics.
Um it's such an incredibly fertile field
that uh I I found it to be an incredible
education.
How would you describe yourself? How do
you go from, you know, poker player to
software engineer? That's such a
big difference. And then crypto. It's
like
very different, right? How do you
describe yourself? Are you a fast
learner?
Just trying to understand how that
works.
Yeah, I mean, look, I'm
I am somebody who picks things up um not
just quickly, but with a lot of energy.
And I think that's the biggest
difference. I know I know a lot of
people who are smart. I know a lot of
people who can learn things quickly. Um
but, the the way that my friends
describe me and the thing that I think
it it was easy to tell a long time ago
would maybe be different is that when
I'm convinced that this thing is the
right thing for me to do,
I throw myself into it with everything
I've got. Um and I'm very very quickly
able to cut the old thing and start the
new thing.
And most people really struggle with
that. You know, they're like, "Oh, I've
spent so much of my life learning this
thing and you know, it's I'm so
respected and you know, all my friends
know this about me. My mom loves this
about me. And I'm going to throw all
that away and go do this other thing cuz
I think it's more important."
Um
And you know, when I was younger and I
was doing this where like, you know, I
I studied English and philosophy in
school.
I have a you know, a bachelor's degree
in in in the humanities. And you know,
most people were like, "Well, you should
go to law school." And I was like,
"Okay, I guess I should go to law
school." And so, I studied for the LSAT
and I like supplied to a bunch of law
schools.
And I realized I think fairly late that
I was like, "Oh, I'm probably not going
to finish this if I do this." Like I'm
exactly the kind of person I was like
reading about people who dropped out of
law school and who like got saddled with
hundreds of thousands of dollars in
debt.
And I I just realized reading this that
like, "I'm definitely one of those
people. I'm totally one of those people
that I'm going to spend 2 years learning
as hard as I can and then be like, wait,
this is a total waste of my time. What
am I doing? I should go build a
business."
Um
And so, I was like, "Oh, I should just
skip that. I should just like skip that
and go to Silicon Valley
where I want to build a business." And
so, I I came to Silicon Valley and I
decided, "Okay, well, what do I What do
you need to do to learn a business when
you have no business skills?"
And the answer is well, you should learn
how to code because coding is the only
thing that you don't need a credential
for. You if you're good at coding, you
can just get a job. And so, I was like,
"Okay, I need to go learn how to code.
How do you do that?" The answer is you
okay, go to go take one of these coding
boot camps, learn very quickly how to
code, and if you outwork everybody else,
then maybe you'll be able to get a job
in the tech industry despite the fact
that you have this weird background with
no
formal skills. Um and so, I was like,
"Okay, I will do that and I will work
nights and weekends. I'll stay there
later than anybody else and I will just
learn how to code."
And I did that. Um and so, along this
time, you know, at at that time I wasn't
a big successful guy, you know, I'd been
successful as a poker player, but then I
left all that behind and started over.
And so, my friends were like, "Haseeb,
what is wrong with you?
You just like you decide like, 'Oh, I'm
going to do law school.' You spend all
this time studying for the tests and
applying to schools and you just leave
it all
and you go to Silicon Valley to go do
this other thing? Like you're you can't
stick to anything.
Like your your problem is that you are
so flighty and you just constantly
change your mind." And I'm like, "No,
no, no, no, no, you don't get it. I
didn't know a damn thing when I applied
to law school. You know, I didn't I
completely didn't understand the world.
And the more that I learn about the
world, the more I realize, 'No, no, no,
I should not be doing that. I should be
doing this instead.'"
And so, when I got out of my job at a
tech company
and I was like, "Hey,
what's going on in the world that's most
interesting to me?" I think crypto. Um
actually, when I when I when I left
Airbnb, so I was working at Airbnb as a
software engineer,
um I remember uh writing down on a piece
of paper
uh what I knew that I wanted to build a
company. That was like my
just the thing in my mind is that I
should build a company.
>> Yeah, what company? What should I build
in? And uh there were two fields that I
thought about going into. The first one
was crypto and the second one was AI.
Now, this was in 20
>> Well, this was Uh this was 2016.
It was 2016. Wow. Um now, at the time AI
was not like what it is today, right? AI
was basically you need a machine
learning PhD in order to be a real
meaningful contributor at the at the
frontier of AI. And so, you know, what I
told myself is like, "Look, um
if I go into AI today, I'm playing from
behind.
The people who are really contributing
in this industry are machine learning
PhDs who've been doing this for a long
long time and like I'll always be from
behind because I have this weird
non-conventional background.
But, if I go into crypto,
in crypto, nobody knows anything. There
are no crypto PhDs. Everybody just
figured this out 10 minutes ago. You
know, it's a brand new industry, no
rules.
Everybody is learning at the same time.
And so, I'm like, "Well, I bet I can
also learn. I can learn just as much as
anyone else can." Um and that's what
ended up convincing me to choose crypto
over AI. At that time, I knew almost
nothing about crypto.
Uh I knew Bitcoin, I knew Ethereum, I
learned about the DAO hack.
And that was all I knew. You know, I
just knew that it was crazy and that it
was super interesting. Um and so, that's
what ended up leading me going into
crypto. So, again, I think from the
perspective of people at the time, it
looked like "Wow, Haseeb, you're so
impulsive. You know, you left this great
tech job to go to this like crazy, you
know, bubbly, stupid little industry
with nothing going on.
Uh like why are you doing that? Like
once again, you're you're just super
flighty." Um
And when I look back on that, I'm like,
"No, no, no, no. The the the property
that I had that very few people I knew
at the time had
was that when I'm convicted in
something,
I go all in.
And I say, "Great. I'm going to chase
this as hard as I can. And if I'm wrong,
then I'll change my mind and I'll go do
something else."
Um
And I was just convinced that I was
right.
So, even when I came into crypto in
2017, you know, that was the the height
of the market and the the the the
craziness of the ICO boom.
By 2018, it was all collapsing. You
know, I had just become an investor at
Metastable and you know, just started
learning the ropes of VC.
And just as I was doing that, everybody
around me who came in the industry at
the same time left.
Because they were all like, "Oh,
this was this was all a mirage. This was
all None of this is real."
And I was convinced that no, no, no, no,
you guys are overreacting.
You guys don't have enough conviction in
this space.
This space is going to be absolutely
huge.
And like the future of money
is absolutely going to be changed
forever by what was invented in this
industry. I was just completely
confident that they were all wrong.
And so I stuck it out in this industry
as an investor and I've been here for,
you know, coming up on 10 years now.
Okay, if you were starting your career
today,
would you pick crypto or AI?
I would pick AI for sure.
Uh-oh. I'd pick AI.
Yeah.
No, because crypto
crypto is a lot more mature today than
it was at the time that I came into it.
Um at the time that I came into crypto,
crypto really needed someone like me.
Mhm.
Not that I was that special, but more
that like crypto just needed people.
Um it needed smart people to like come
in and start thinking about all the hard
problems that they were going to face.
Um it's not that crypto doesn't need
people today, it obviously does, but
crypto needs people, fintech needs
people, you know, biotech needs people,
everything needs people because there's
a lot of problems to solve in the world.
Um but what needs people more than
anything else and is still totally
undecided, still in the infancy, is
complete wild west, that's AI today.
You know, and so I think a lot of people
in crypto, they get really anxious, they
say, "Oh no, you know, people are going
to AI. Oh no, what was me?" I'm like,
"This is a stupid mentality. This is a
stupid mentality. It's a big world,
there's always multiple things going on.
And what um
you know, you your goal is as a somebody
in crypto should not be that the rest of
the world does not advance.
You should not want the rest of
technology to stay still, right? You
should want the rest of technology to
evolve like crazy because crypto is the
most cyberpunk futuristic technology
there could possibly be.
Crypto is going to succeed in a world
where everything else changes.
If everything stays the same
and, you know, the the year 2040 looks
like the year 1990, then crypto's going
to fail.
Crypto is designed for the future, but
if the future doesn't come, there's no
one to use all this stuff.
So, that's why I think it's very foolish
for people who to start thinking that
crypto wins when AI fails, it's the
opposite. When you started, crypto was,
you know, very new to everybody, so
people had equal chances, right? Right
now, AI, there are people that are so
good and people that are just learning
it for the first time.
I think this is over I think this is
overrated. I know, I don't think this is
true. So, if you listen to Dario, the
CEO of Anthropic, [clears throat] what
he says is that uh you know, this was
just a few years ago when when Anthropic
was first growing as a business,
he said that we actually don't try to
hire machine learning PhDs.
We just try to hire smart people.
Because machine learning PhDs, most of
them were learning machine learning in a
time before LLMs.
And all of that stuff is mostly useless
today.
Because it's just not the way that
machines learn anymore. Machines don't
learn the way they did 10 years ago. So,
some guy who got a machine learning PhD
10 years ago, they don't know a damn
thing about LLMs.
They don't know about transformers.
Transformers were invented 10 years ago.
So, is it really possible that somebody
who got a machine learning PhD 10 years
ago happened to study transformers? We
didn't know that transformers were going
to control everything in the future 10
years ago. So, now, if you if you get a
Stanford PhD today, then okay, you're
learning about LLMs for sure.
But um so much is yet to be written and
so much of like everybody, you know, go
talk to all these people working in the
field, they're drinking from a firehose
every day. I remember what that was
like.
If you were in crypto back in the day
that I was there or like in DeFi summer
or like when when all this stuff was
changing in real time, it's the same
feeling. Everything is changing all the
time and somebody who joins
has just as much ability to keep up with
the latest and greatest as somebody
who's been doing it for 10 years. Now,
it's not to say there's no gap, of
course you do, there's stuff you got to
learn, but is it really true that it's
like, "Oh, you're late?"
No.
No, that's ridiculous. You know, there's
a story from Marc Andreessen when he he
arrived in Silicon Valley and I think it
was like 1997, right? Young young kid
from Ohio.
And what he says is that, you know, by
the time that I had showed up in Silicon
Valley,
there was already, you know, Cisco and
Silicon Graphics and, you know, all
these great companies were already huge.
You know, I was reading about it on the
cover of magazines.
And I, this little kid, come all the way
here to Silicon Valley and I was worried
that the whole thing was already over.
That I was too late.
Right? He thought he was too late in
about the internet. The internet had
barely even started at the time that he
showed up. So, no. If you're showing up
today,
you are in the first chapter
in the first book of what's going to
happen in in the future of this
technology.
I remember before ChatGPT, people are
saying the same thing about crypto, that
this is the early internet and everybody
is so early, but now, you know, it's
only been a couple years.
People are talking about the next thing
now.
It's well, that's the thing, it's not
the next thing. It's another thing and
there will always be another thing. But
the reality, look, so, you know, in the
very early internet, right?
We had um
very different form factors that we had
once the internet matured. So, if you
think about Web 2, right? What do we
call Web 2? Web 2 is the whole idea that
you can read and write to the internet,
you've got comment sections, you've got
social media, you've got all this stuff
didn't exist in Web 1, right? Web 1 was
like static page, you you have a home
page.
And you go to the home page and you read
the home page. You know, people I I
remember at the time
um there was a lot of excitement because
Time magazine
was on the internet, they had a web
page. People were like, "Oh, Time
magazine's going to rule the internet
because they they came to the internet
first, they're going to crush it." You
know, I think it's the same thing as
like people worrying about, "Oh, you
know, Stripe now has a product, so
they're going to they're going to
control stablecoins." It's ridiculous,
right? Like this has always been the
concern of people when they see big
companies coming into these spaces.
Um
but
the the reality is that okay, when you
first started to see Facebook
and you first started to see, you know,
these Web 2 era companies start to form
their products,
would did that mean that like, "Okay,
Facebook now has a newsfeed,
is it basically onto the next thing? Is
the internet over?"
No. It was another 20 years of the
internet eating everything. Just growing
and growing and growing and growing
until it's consumed the whole world,
right? Now, the the number of products
that emerged after like 2010
became way fewer, right? By 2010, we
already had Facebook, we had LinkedIn,
we had Snapchat, we had almost all these
companies already existed by 2010.
But they had not grown to the extent
that they did. Like the only major
social media company that emerged after
2010 was ByteDance and TikTok.
That had not emerged yet, but YouTube,
all this stuff already existed at that
time. Um so, the story from 2010 to 2027
was just eating everything.
That was the story from then on forward.
So, it was not new products, it was not
new companies, it was the companies that
were there growing to dominate the
world.
And I suspect that that's the stage that
we're in with crypto. We kind of know
the shape that crypto's going to take
now.
We can sort of see, okay, there's going
to be DeFi, there's going to be
stablecoins, there's going to be some
applications, there's going to be
Bitcoin,
there's going to be some on-chain
you know, programmable rails and smart
contracts you can use to facilitate
different kinds of you know, financial
agreements.
It's probably not going to be a billion
games, it's probably not going to be,
you know, all this other stuff that we
talked about. We kind of see the shape
of it, right? But the scale
is only going to get bigger and bigger.
So, if you were an early Facebook user
and you're kind of like, "Well, what
really even changed? I already had a
Facebook feed, you know, in 2010. The
internet got boring, there's nothing
more going on."
And the answer is like, "Okay, yeah,
kind of." That's sort of true, but it's
also not true. Because, you know, as the
saying goes, quantity is a quality of
its own.
When the scale gets big enough,
it really becomes qualitatively
different.
When stablecoins are the dominant way
that money is moving through the world
internationally, it actually really
changes the way that stablecoins are. It
changes the way that blockchains are. It
changes the way that you interact with
all this stuff, the way they get
regulated, the way they get treated. So,
um
I think that's where
this technology is going is that we see
the shape of it and we know how it's
going to fit, but it just grows bigger
and bigger and bigger.
Whereas AI,
we don't know.
We don't know what it's going to look
like. We don't know even, you know, it's
not a question of how big it's going to
get, it's what is your life with an AI
agent going to look like in 10 years?
Who knows?
There is this narrative that uh crypto
is built for AI and robots, not humans.
And does that, you know, echo to what
you just said, it's going to be bigger
and a few players dominating the whole
field.
Mhm. altcoins.
Yeah. I mean, crazy projects.
Probably it will happen over the next 5
to 10 years that a lot of altcoins will
you'll you'll see this sort of um
this larger and larger divide
between the really successful scale
projects and the ones that never got to
scale.
Um now this is normal, right? I mean,
think of social media platforms. Social
media again was the biggest most
important trend of the last 20 years.
If you look at some of the biggest
companies in the world, almost all of
them are some kind of social media
companies.
Um but
again, there were almost no no new
social media companies after 2010.
So early on, there were a bunch of them,
right? There was, you know, Foursquare
and there was, you know, um
Yelp and MySpace and this and that and
blah blah blah. And over time, there was
consolidation.
I think you should expect to see the
same thing within crypto is that there
probably is not going to be you know,
400 layer ones.
Um but there's also not going to be just
one layer one. There's going to be some
number of them, the same way that
there's Facebook, there's LinkedIn, you
know, there's there's WeChat, there's
there's uh you know
Instagram. So, there are genuinely
different modalities. They serve
genuinely different uh types of use
cases.
But
there's not room for infinite of them.
And that is going to change over time as
the market matures.
Um
but I would say in 10 years, so to
answer your question is crypto going to
be used for AIs or is it going to be
primarily used by humans?
I think one of the things that's obvious
the more time you spend on it is that
humans
don't naturally click
with crypto.
Crypto is really weird for humans. Yeah,
so okay. I mean
think about every time that you've tried
to get a family member to use crypto.
And you've got to explain to them
yeah, you got to explain to them like a
wallet, right? And a wallet is like a
big long string of hexadecimal
characters. It's not human readable,
right? And you have to tell them like no
no no, when you send this thing, there's
18 decimal points
that you can add to this thing, which is
like human beings, why do we have 18
decimal point? Why isn't it just cents,
you know? Why can't it be like dollars
and cents? Like that seems way simpler.
Um you know, why why is it that I can
you send a transaction and all my money
can get hacked?
Right? That that seems really weird.
That shouldn't that seems like that
shouldn't happen. Uh why is it when I
sign this transaction, I get this weird
long string that I can't read as a human
being and like shouldn't it be in
English? Like why is it like this?
There's all these things
that are part of crypto
that we do you know, at this point we're
crypto natives, we think of this as
normal, right? We think of it as like,
yeah, you got to check the approvals and
you got to make sure that you don't get
hacked and like you got to never click
on drainers and always check the domain
and like we we know all of these things
because we've been in the space for a
very long time, but the original story
that I was told when I first got into
crypto back in 2016
right? That story was that smart
contracts
would change the way that people did
legal agreements.
Is that instead of signing a legal
contract, you would sign a smart
contract. That's why we you know, that's
why we call them contracts, right? It's
the analogy between legal contracts and
and code. And the idea is that okay, you
and I want to strike a deal, we're going
to sign a smart contract and that smart
contract is going to check the outcome.
And look, I've been doing this now for,
you know, 10 years
and I have never done an investment via
smart contract.
Every time I do an investment, I sign a
legal contract, okay? Now, I'm one of
the most sophisticated firms in the
industry. We manage billions of dollars.
We've literally got engineers on staff.
Why are we not And we're you know, we're
our counterparties are other crypto
startups.
And yet we're not signing deals with
smart contracts. Why are we not doing
that? The answer is because
we trust the legal contract more than we
trust the smart contract.
Because a legal contract, we know if
something goes wrong
who is going to decide the outcome. The
answer is a judge. A judge will decide
the outcome. And the judge will probably
not include a bug in the contract.
Right? If the contract is written in a
weird way, the judge is going to make
sure it does something pretty
reasonable, right? But if a smart
contract is written in a weird way and
there's a bug in the smart contract, the
EVM is not going to do something
reasonable.
The EVM is going to do exactly what the
bytecode says.
And that's not what I want. That's not
what my counterparty wants. We both want
a reasonable thing to happen. And so the
reality is that like we are better at
understanding what will happen in a
legal contract than in a smart contract.
But AIs are different. Okay, AIs are
different. Why are AIs different? AIs
are different because they actually can
easily understand a smart contract.
They can much more easily understand
code than they can understand a legal
contract. Okay, now why do I say that? A
legal contract is by its nature random.
What's the randomness in a in a legal
contract? The randomness is, okay, so
first of all, I've written this contract
with you. First, is this contract going
to be enforceable?
Sometimes it's not. Like for example,
let's say I put you under duress. That
means that you can negate the contract.
Uh you can't tell from the contract
whether you're under duress. I can't
tell. But if you can prove it to a
judge, you can negate the contract.
Okay. Second, what jurisdiction are we
going to be in, right? You're in Asia,
I'm in the US.
Where is this contract going to be
adjudicated? Maybe we say we're going to
do it here, but maybe we fight about it
and we do it over there. And now the
rules are totally different, right?
Third thing is, okay, let's say we
actually go to court. We go to court,
who's the judge?
The judge is random. It's literally done
by a lottery. When you go to court, they
pull a ball out of a hat to decide who
your judge is. And some judges like you,
some judges like this, some judges like
that. And then if you if you go to a
full jury trial, then they literally
choose 12 random people off the street
who are going to be the people who
decide your case, right? Okay, so if
you're an AI agent
there's so many random pieces of
information
to help you understand what's going to
happen if I sign this agreement with
this person. I I literally cannot guess.
There's randomness embedded in that
process. But if I sign a smart contract
with this person, I can read every
single piece of bytecode. I can simulate
the whole thing. I can formally verify
the code and I can do that all within
the span of seconds.
The the smart contract is entirely
deterministic, but the legal contract is
not.
And so an AI agent you know, in a way,
like the people who built Ethereum, they
thought
well, everybody will just read the code
and obviously we'll all read the code
and we'll understand exactly what it
does and we'll trust it. We'll trust it
more than we trust the legal system.
The problem with the story is that the
people who wrote Ethereum
are all autistic programmers.
And autistic programmers, they really
feel like, oh, I trust the code. I read
the code and it's it's it's great. Uh
the problem is that we're not like that.
Most human beings are not like autistic
programmers. But AI agents
are more like autistic programmers than
they're like the rest of us.
And so in a way, AI agents are kind of
the perfect customer.
All of the things that you have to do,
right? Like the fact that you have to
keep your your private key completely
secret and never show it to anybody
else,
otherwise you'll lose all your money.
Very unintuitive for human beings.
Completely intuitive for an AI agent. An
AI agent already knows what an API key
is. It knows how to keep secrets. Um and
so an AI agent can can handle that. Uh
it already knows how to sign a smart
contract. It already knows how to read
code. It already knows, you know, all of
the things that you would need to do in
order to interact with a with a
blockchain-based uh system.
And so that's why I claim, you know, you
imagine I have an agent, you have an
agent, we're both asleep. Our agents
make a deal with each other and they
just do a few rounds of negotiating the
the the code of a smart contract. They
agree. They sign the smart contract.
They engage in some kind of deal. We
wake up and the deal's already done.
That is the future
in which smart contracts are going to be
the predominant way that agents are able
to collaborate with each other and
actually build trust in each other even
if the principals, even if you and I
don't know each other and don't have to
know each other. So, if our AI agents
sign a deal and I do not honor the deal,
who goes to jail?
Well, if the if the deal involves you
like you, the human being, then the AI
agent, my AI agent
basically can't underwrite it itself,
right? Because just knowing the smart
contract isn't enough to say, okay, is
Bonnie actually going to follow through
on the deal?
The smart contract can't verify that.
So, if if the good provided is digital
and most of the time when AI agents are
collaborating, you know, the the they're
exchanging some kind of digital goods.
They're not you know, you're not
physically sending me something in the
mail or, you know, you're not going to
agree to post me on your podcast or
whatever. Um most of the time if two AI
agents are interacting with each other
the thing that they're interacting over
is digital in nature. So, maybe it's
like, hey, you're going to work with me
and you're going to help me write this
article or you're going to help me do
this whatever.
Um or you're going to expend these
tokens for me or you're going to let me
use an API that you have access to that
I don't, right? So, maybe I'm in the US,
I can access the newest Anthropic model,
but because you're in Asia, you can't
access it. And so you say, "Hey, I'll
pay you if you can give me some tokens
from your thing." And I say, "Okay, I'll
do that." Smart contract verifies it.
The end.
Talking about this, there is this
concept called ghost GDP. So, all the AI
agents, you know
buy and sell from each other billions of
times a second, but
the economy or like it seems like it's
booming, right? But no money actually
goes to human pocket. Now what? I think
this is a it's it's an important concept
of ghost GDP.
Um what ghost GDP is trying to get at is
this idea that economic value has been
created but not measured.
So um let's let's let's just think
today. We already have a lot of ghost
GDP that's created by AI. So, let me
just give you an example. Um so most
people I know use ChatGPT for some kind
of health care. Okay. Now normally, if
you were being provided that health care
advice, you would have to go to a
doctor.
You would have to go pay you know, pay
your hospital visit or pay your local
practitioner visit and you know, go book
with their assistant and have set up a
time and go in there and say, "Hey doc,
what's going on? Oh, I have this rash. I
have this thing. Oh, I'm not sleeping
well or oh, you know, whatever. I'm
looking at this medication. It's it's
causing me this issue." Um and they
would say, "Oh, no, it's fine." blah
blah blah and they'd send you home,
right? what used to happen, okay? Today,
you ask ChatGPT, you get the answer in 2
seconds, done. Okay? Now, that is a
service that's been provided to you that
would normally cost you a lot of money.
But, right now, you are getting it
basically at the marginal cost of just
your ChatGPT subscription.
You're getting it for free, right?
>> Yeah.
>> That is ghost GDP.
That is economic value that was created
that in an alternate world, there would
be an exchange of goods, right? There
would be an exchange of service that
they pay taxes, you pay taxes on that
whole transaction. You pay sales tax,
they pay payroll tax, right? But, now,
there's no record that that ever
happened. The government doesn't know
that there were services provided. It
doesn't know that you received these
valuable services of getting this
medical advice. Um and that you were
willing to pay for that by buying your
ChatGPT subscription, right? Or
sometimes, you know, for a lot of
people, it's like even free.
Um so, these services are actually
wealth.
You are wealthier when you get services
for free.
Uh the same way that if I gave you
bananas for free, you'd be like, "Well,
now I'm wealthy. I got more bananas,
right?" When I give you health care,
health care is also a valuable thing
that you just got. But, there's no
measurement of it. It doesn't show up in
GDP, doesn't show up in income, doesn't
show up in payroll, doesn't show up
anywhere.
So, this is one of the problems with
using GDP as the principal measure of
the wealth of a society is that these
kinds of services that are too cheap to
meter,
uh where you're getting something that
would otherwise have cost you a lot of
money and you're now getting it for
free,
this does not get measured by the way
that we measure GDP.
Uh now, you can look at that and say,
"Oh my god, that's terrible. That means
that there's going to be an economic
collapse." Um that's wrong. It's the
wrong way to understand what's
happening.
The right way to understand what's
happening is that everybody in society
just got richer.
That's the right way to understand
what's happening, right? If you had a
machine that could magically manifest
bananas
in your house, right? Just literally
transmogrify them and pull them out of
outer space, okay?
That would not show up in GDP.
Nobody bought anything, nobody sold
anything. It would not look like society
got richer. You'd say, "GDP was flat
this year. No one got any richer and
society is exactly the same as it was
last year." Well, no, it's not. We all
got magical banana machine. We have
infinite bananas. We are insanely rich
now because everybody can have as many
bananas as they want. Um that's kind of
what just happened with ChatGPT. And so,
this ghost GDP concept, you know, the
way that Citronelle, the uh article that
went viral about this, it kind of paints
this as a disastrous concept is that
ghost GDP is really bad and means that
somehow this is going to lead to some
kind of social collapse. Um
I think the right way to understand
ghost GDP is that that's what it looks
like when when you get richer from a
technology that creates a ton of value.
Is rich the right word? It is my Maybe
my life my quality of life improved, but
did did I get richer?
You got richer. So, when you receive
more goods and services, you get richer.
So, what is the point of having money?
Let's let's maybe ask a deeper question,
right? You say richer, usually what you
mean is I have more money.
What's the point of having more money?
Money is a currency that you can use to
trade for
goods and services. Okay? So, if you're
now spending less on other goods and
services, you're spending less on health
care,
that means you have more money to spend
on other things.
If you would otherwise have spent that
money on going to the doctor and having
that doctor prescribe you a blah blah
blah, right? Now, we have more doctors
who are less busy and they can go and
treat other things. That lowers the cost
of health care and it means that you're
getting health care for free,
which means that you can spend the money
you would have spent on health care on
other things.
So, when a handyman, right? Normally,
you'd have a handyman come in and help
you fix some, you know, it's your your
AC is miswired, okay? Now, you take
ChatGPT, you point it at the the wiring
and you say, "Tell me what to do." And
ChatGPT says, "Oh, move this thing over
here, move the green wire here and the
blue wire here. Done." You do that, it
works, right? Okay. This is ghost GDP.
You say, "Okay, well, did that make me
richer? How is that richer? I just I
just helped uh you know, unwire my
thing." Well, the answer is that you
would have to go pay a handyman.
Handyman would have to come to your
house.
That person now is freed up to go do
something else and you have 75 bucks in
your pocket that you wouldn't otherwise
have.
Is it possible that because people are
worried about the handyman has nothing
else to do?
Well, so, one, I wouldn't worry about
handyman. Uh there's a lot of work for
handymen [laughter] to do. Um
it it Yeah, it it is it is probably true
that there's going to be downward
pressure on wages for some of the things
that are directly competitive with AI.
But, the reality is that, you know, for
handyman, most of what they do is not
fix trivial little problems. You know,
like the trivial little problems are the
things that you're now saving from your
handyman, but you are not going to go do
like a deep HVAC repair with ChatGPT,
right? Like that that's just not going
to happen. Yet.
Not even yet. Like you don't have the
tools, you know, you don't have like the
measurement. Like, you know, if you've
seen like really serious HVAC stuff, you
need a lot of stuff in order to like
actually debug an HVAC. Um like you
might need to get it replaced, you might
need to like, you know, check, "Oh, hey,
the the the coolant is not enough or the
insulation is bad." So, that kind of
expertise, like ChatGPT can tell you,
"Oh, you know, go tear out the
insulation and go inside and you're
going to do that? Or you're going to
say, "All right, screw this. This is
beyond my pay grade. I'm going to just
go hire an HVAC guy." Um so, I think
that's largely the answer is that and
obviously, there's a lot of manual labor
that's involved in a lot of handyman
type tasks. So, now look, I worry a lot
more about programmers.
I worry a lot more about doctors. Uh I
think if anything, actually, doctors are
probably the most exposed to AI. Um
because if you think about doctors,
like, you know, what is a doctor? A
doctor is somebody who's gotten a lot of
education,
um but actually doesn't have that much
in the way of physical skills,
right? The the reason why a doctor is
the most highly paid person in the
medical system is because they're the
most knowledgeable.
But, a doctor is not a surgeon.
A doctor is not a physician's assistant.
A doctor is not a nurse. Their job is
not to physically do the thing. Their
job is to use their head and to figure
out what is the diagnosis, what do I
prescribe, what do I know, um and have
the bedside manner,
right? But, today,
ChatGPT is as good as most doctors and
better than most doctors.
Mhm. And it it it knows more. It never
gets tired, never gets lazy, never gets
short, never gets angry. It's always
going to be polite to you. And if
somebody needs to actually draw blood,
the doctor generally doesn't do that.
The nurse does that, right? The
physician's assistant does that. The
doctor's job was to have knowledge in
their head.
And those jobs are the ones that are
going to be most at risk
because in the same way, you know, we
used to have calculators,
calculators meant human beings who
calculated.
That's what a calculator meant. It was a
human with an abacus who would add
numbers together to help you when you
are trying to do business tasks.
Today, a calculator is a little machine.
All those people who did calculations
are gone.
In the same way,
the idea that it's a job to memorize
facts and hold them in your head, we are
going to look back at that in 15 years
and say, "Wow, that's so antiquated."
It's going to look to us the same way
that calculators look to us of human
calculators with abacuses manually doing
a bunch of math.
Is that also going to bankrupt all the
middlemen services, the apps, Uber Eats,
Expedia,
DoorDash?
>> No, not at all. Not at all. Why Why do
you say that?
So, this is again one of the things in
the Citronelle article that I thought
was completely just a total
misunderstanding of these business
models.
Um
there are a lot of competitors to
DoorDash
already, right? His article was like,
"Well, well, somebody could just vibe
code the next DoorDash and then all the
dashers will, you know, check all the
apps and blah blah blah." Um the the
primary hard thing about DoorDash is not
writing a crud app.
The hard part about DoorDash is the
logistics network. That's what's hard
about DoorDash, right? The hard part
about DoorDash is the dispute
resolution. That's what's hard about
DoorDash is that, you know, somebody
shows up at your house, the food is cold
or they got the wrong food, who's right?
How do you decide this person should get
a refund or this person should not? How
do you make sure the error rate is
sufficiently low? How do you make sure
people trust that every time I order
DoorDash, the right thing happens or I
get my money back? That is a really hard
problem that has very little to do with
software.
It has much more to do with just like
how do you cultivate and run an
effective business with contractors that
you keep track of and make sure that
they're they're performing at a very
high level, that they're well trained,
that they're getting the right feedback,
that they're in the right place at the
right time. How do you make sure all the
merchants are on there so people can
all, you know, find all the food at the
right time.
All this stuff is much more about
logistics
and about reputation
than it is just purely about software.
And so, that's why, you know, there are
a lot of competitors to DoorDash and
like new ones spin up every day. Um but,
they can't take a bite out of DoorDash's
meal.
What about Airbnb?
Well, so, I used to work at Airbnb, so I
know Airbnb very well. Um there were a
lot of Airbnb competitors. So, there's,
you know, there's VRBO, there's uh
what's that one that's like HomeAway or
something.
Um
The hard part about Airbnb, same thing.
The hard part about Airbnb is not how
can I make an app that lists houses and
lets you look at them.
Actually, if you tell an AI to make an
Airbnb clone, it can do it in about 10
minutes. It's extremely trivial to
create something that looks like Airbnb.
The hard part about Airbnb is again, the
logistics, which is that you are going
to a house.
You are going to stay in that house.
That house had better be safe.
Had better be what it purports to be.
Had better actually deliver the place
that I'm staying and not double book it
with somebody else such that when I show
up, someone's already in there, right?
If that happens even once,
much less twice, I'm out forever. I'm
never coming back. I'm not even going to
try this again because that's the
scariest I've ever heard.
This kind of stuff where it's
free-standing software
that all of the state for that software
is yours is your state it's hosted
locally
those are the businesses that are most
threatened by AI.
Right? If Airbnb's code got leaked, who
cares?
Who's who's on Airbnb because of the the
wonderful code they wrote? You know,
who's not building an Airbnb competitor
cuz they don't know how to write the
code? So, when you think about this way
it suddenly becomes very obvious the
difference between the businesses who
would really be impaired by somebody
going and writing a clone and the
businesses that, you know, if their code
base leaked
whatever, you know, who cares? Boohoo.
Do you think in the future we're going
to, you know, be able to retire early
and have a better quality of life? I
think people are trying to imagine
because AI is so revolutionary. Now now
now what? Like what is our life going to
look like in 20 years?
Are we going to sit on a beach
>> [sighs]
>> all day?
>> to say. Yeah, I don't know.
>> 10 years, let's start with 10 years.
10 years, definitely not 10 years. 10
years is not enough for it to fully
diffuse through the economy.
Um look, 20 years here's what I'll say.
If you look at the history
of working hours
um over the last call it, you know, 150
years since the Industrial Revolution.
Um
do you think that human beings have been
starting to work more or work less over
time?
More.
People are working more. People are
working more than they ever have. Damn.
Now, the interesting thing is that like
they're working more even in rich
countries
and even in the richest percentages of
those countries, people are working
more.
So, it's not true that you you would
think that like, okay, well, why aren't
we all like
you know, Victorian aristocrats that
once we get super rich, we just like
laze all day and we hang out in the
court and we watch people, you know,
these little protégés play music. Why
don't we just hang out all day and eat
crumpets and like talk about gossip?
And the answer is that
>> easier jobs?
Um well, we're certainly doing easier
jobs than like, you know, backbreaking
labor or like the you know, kind of
conditions under which people worked.
Like I mean, people used to, you know,
people just 50 years ago they worked
without AC, you know, they worked
without There was no TV, there were no
phones, there was no email, there was no
anything. So, like obviously in that
sense, jobs are way easier than they
were before. Like look, I'm I'm taking
this call from home.
I didn't even have to leave, right? I've
I've literally been in my house all day.
Like I don't have to commute, I don't
have to go on a train, I don't have to
deal with, you know, all the of
like hanging out and waiting. People
didn't even have phones when they were
on their commutes before, you know? So,
like yes, our jobs are way easier
than jobs were in the past. No doubt
about that. Um
that being said, and you know, obviously
I I do knowledge work, so I'm I'm
somebody who my job is particularly
easy, but even among, you know, people
who are doing physical labor, the kind
of physical labor people were doing 100
years ago is unrecognizable brutal
compared to the physical labor that
people do today.
Um
so uh now, why do I say all that?
There's always been this thinking
um for a long time, even from the time
of Adam Smith and and John Maynard
Keynes, this idea that as people got
richer they were going to work less and
there was going to be more time for
leisure, more times for play.
And what we have learned over time is
that that's not actually what human
beings want to do.
The richer that they get, the more that
they want to work. And that's very
counterintuitive.
And I think the answer of why this is
the case is that
people actually really want
to be valuable.
It's a deep human need to be valuable.
And
the the you know, there's there's this
amazing study that showed that
um if you take, you know, elderly
people, let's say who are like 63, 64,
right? Let's say let's say the age of
retirement is 65 in this country, okay?
If you're 63 or 64 and you are
unemployed
your quality of life is very bad.
People who are unemployed generally feel
very bad about themselves, they tend to,
you know, sleep poorly, they tend to get
depressed. Uh it's very very bad for
your psychology and your well-being to
be unemployed, right? Not because
unemployment like, you know, physically
makes you uh that well off. Even if you
have a strong social safety net, that
unemployed people are taken care of,
they can eat, they can, you know,
whatever, live live relatively normal
lives, still people feel terrible
when they're unemployed. Now, the
interesting thing that happens is that
even with a strong social safety net
somebody who's unemployed at 64
when they turn 65, they're not
unemployed anymore, they're retired now.
And the moment that you switch from
unemployed to retired, even if your
social benefits did not change
suddenly people are way happier.
Now, why is that?
Why is it that people feel totally okay
with themselves when they're retired,
but they feel terrible about themselves
when they're unemployed? And the answer
is because
society tells you
when you're 63, 64 that you are not
useful.
You are not contributing to society.
You're not contributing to the tribe.
And human beings, we're deeply social
animals. We need to feel like we are
being useful to our tribes. But when you
turn 65, it's like, oh no, no. You've
been released from that responsibility.
It's not that you're useless to the
tribe, you are an elder statesman of the
tribe. You are now on the senior
council. You are one of the elderly
retired people, you get to boss people
around, you get to tell them what to do,
tell them about all your wisdom. Welcome
to the club. Right? And just that change
in mentality makes people suddenly feel
much better.
And I think this is a large part of the
reason why we should not expect that
just because we're going to have much
more of material wealth
just because we're going to have a lot
less of these kind of knowledge work
type jobs to go around that people are
going to spend all their time
playing video games. I mean, some people
obviously will, but the more likely
thing is that we are going to find
alternative ways
of valuing each other and showing each
other that we're valuable.
We're going to still feel the need to be
needed.
And that is going to express itself in
other ways.
So, I suspect there will be a lot more
jobs that we will look now
and say that's really weird that
you know, today if if I told you that
there are going to be a lot more
professional chess players
in the future compared to today
that's like, what? Why are there
professional chess players in the
future? But I predict probably
I think the reason why is that people
will have higher demand
for other high performance humans. They
will find it entertaining.
And watching AIs play chess, I mean, AIs
could already beat the best humans at
chess
20 years ago.
They said, why are there any humans
playing chess? The answer is because we
like to watch them.
That's why there are humans playing
chess, not because we're the best in the
world at it. We're not. We we were
superseded a long time ago. Um you know,
why do we like to watch people play
sports?
Because, you know, is it because the
human form is the best at moving a ball
into a into a hoop?
No, it's not. Actually, we we built
robot robots that can do it way better
than humans a long time ago. But we like
to see what happens when the humans
compete.
Cuz it's very satisfying to
And so, my guess is that you will see a
lot more of these kinds of jobs
which are kind of weird
sort of feels like this is kind of made
up. Why don't we just create like more
demand for sports and for, you know, all
these like stupid things that don't
really advance human civilization? It's
just pure entertainment. Uh I think
there's going to be a lot more demand
for these kinds of things because
everything else is basically being done
by machines.
Um so, there's going to be a lot of
unintuitive things. A lot of
entertainment, right? I mean, that's
that's actually what happens as
societies get richer. That's what
happens as societies get richer. Poor
societies don't have entertainers.
Mhm. They don't exist, right?
Entertainment in in very poor, you know,
think about back to Victorian England
entertainment was a very rare job
because most people could not afford to
be entertained.
They couldn't afford to pay other humans
to entertain them.
Um today entertainment is very cheap
because of mass mass media and, you
know, you can just watch TikTok and the
marginal cost of providing you TikTok,
it's so cheap they literally give it to
you for free.
That's how cheap entertainment has
become.
Um
but, you know, I think the the provision
of services
the the ways in which we as human beings
do things for each other that nobody
else can do
um and the reality is a lot of physical
tasks.
Like robotics is going to be a lot
harder to crack than intelligence.
We can already see that. Um intelligence
has blown us away in the progress.
And if you look at robotics, you know,
you know that video of the the robot
trying to put dishes in the dishwasher,
you know, like we're very very far away
today from robots actually being able to
help you relative to a human.
So, I think there's going to be a long
span of time where you see the
intelligence and intelligent tasks
pulled in this direction and physical
tasks pushed pulled in the opposite
direction. Actually, people who can do
physical tasks
are probably going to be paid more in
the future.
A lot more in the future. That would be
my guess.
We talk a lot about AI, but you just
closed a fund
of $650 million on crypto.
Uh on crypto.
Yeah.
So, you still believe in crypto?
Of course I believe in crypto.
Look. Why not AI fund?
Well
there's a lot of AI funds. So, there's
there's people already doing that. You
know, they don't need me to do that. Um
the reason why we are raising a crypto
fund, why we raised a crypto fund, is
because we believe in crypto. We believe
crypto's going to be enormous. It's
going to be one of the biggest
technology trends of our lifetimes. Um
you know, I I I wrote this post a while
back called In Defense of Exponentials
where I compare the rise of smart
contract platforms to the rise of
e-commerce in the '90s.
And, you know, e-commerce you know, my
partner Bo, who's one of the founders of
Dragonfly um he
he often describes what it was like in
the early days of e-commerce
when, you know, they'd sit around a
table arguing about who is e-commerce
going to be used for?
You know, is it is it going to be, you
know, only women who use e-commerce cuz
they like to, you know, they like to do
all the shopping, maybe e-commerce is
only going to be for women. Um maybe
e-commerce is only going to be used for,
you know, books and and durable goods,
but there's never going to be for food,
it's never going to be for, you know,
perishables. Um they had all these
different ideas about who's going to use
e-commerce.
And the right answer
was e-commerce is going to be used for
everything.
The right answer was everything. There
is no market for e-commerce. The market
for e-commerce is everything.
So,
in the same way,
I think this is going to be true for
crypto and I think crypto is my
e-commerce.
Crypto is going to be the thing that
over time it's going to eat everything.
It's going to be used for everything.
And now when I look back on it, when you
look back on e-commerce,
e-commerce was this huge enormous
megatrend.
But e-commerce was not as big as the
internet. The internet obviously was
bigger than e-commerce.
Um in the same way,
I think I'm going to look back over the
span of my career and say crypto was
this huge gigantic megatrend that ended
up changing so much.
But crypto was just one part of this
larger wave of the ways in which human
civilization changed with the advent of
AI, with it with the technology with the
the softwareization of everything.
Um
the world never just evolves on one
dimension.
Geopolitics changes, multiple
technologies change. Um you don't have
to be
the one thing that matters
because there is no one thing that
matters. Everything matters. And so
that's why I say I'm very happy to be
investing into crypto. Um but just
because I invest in crypto doesn't mean
that I should be taking my eye off of
everything else that's going to be
changing around it. I love that. Very
well said. Have your investment thesis
changed over the years? You've raised
many rounds, uh 225 million in 2021, 600
650 million in 2022, and now this,
right?
Have you started looking at different
things now?
Um
in many ways our thesis is pretty
similar to what it's always been.
Which is? You know, what what works in
crypto? Like the first ever investment
we made
at Dragonfly was MakerDAO.
That was back in 2018.
Um first ever investment we made was a
stablecoin.
And you know, if you go to today,
we're investing a lot into stablecoins.
We're continuing to invest in the same
trend that we started almost 10 years
ago.
And you know, we continue to invest in
DeFi.
MakerDAO was literally a DeFi protocol.
Uh continue to invest into DeFi and all
the innovations that are happening
there. I mean, everyone's been paying
attention to hyperliquid and the rise of
RWA perps. Um I think it's a huge
megatrend that will continue to grow.
Um continue to invest in infrastructure.
You know, we're investors in double
zero, which is uh you know, a network
layer protocol.
Um we're obviously investors from our
fund three into Monad, into Mega ETH,
which are two of the big infrastructure
projects from this last vintage.
Um
We also invested in Ethena, which, you
know, is obviously we led their seed
round. We're big investors there. Uh
also another DeFi protocol. Um and we
continue to invest in you know, things
that are defining the future. So,
uh if you look at Polymarket, we're big
investors into Polymarket. Um prediction
markets are one of the core ideas in
crypto. Literally, if if prediction
markets had a whole paragraph in the
Ethereum white paper back in 2013
about why this is going to be one of the
primary use cases for smart contracts.
Um and Polymarket has brought it to
existence.
Uh the same thing ultimately is going to
be true for the intersection of crypto
and AI.
Still very early there, but I think
there's going to be a lot of
intersection and a lot of surface area
for us to cover over the coming years.
So,
I think there's a lot to do. We're
actually seeing incredible velocity of
pitches. I thought, you know, usually
beginning of the year is pretty slow for
us as an as investors,
uh but this has been an incredibly
intense start to the year just because
there's so much stuff going on in the
space.
Is it all concentrated in a few
narratives
because of institutions?
Um no, I wouldn't say that's true. I
mean, it's certainly true that
institutions are driving a lot of the
demand for crypto right now because
retail has largely checked out. You
know, since 1010, that's when you saw
the retail bid for crypto really dry up.
And today, if you look at the relative
volumes, you look at, you know, perps
open interest, you look at, you know,
Coinbase downloads on the App Store, uh
you look at all these measures of retail
interest, they're down a lot.
Retail is checked out right now.
And when retail's checked out, all the
prices hurt, but especially altcoin
prices, uh because altcoins are mostly
owned by retail, right? It's not
institutions. Institutions aren't buying
alts. They're buying Bitcoin, they're
buying some ETH, and that's mostly it.
So,
um
all that said,
my mental model of all this stuff is
that
they will come back.
The space is incredibly cyclical. And in
the meantime, um I don't fixate too much
on what the institutions are doing.
Obviously, the institutions matter, but
they're actually not the primary driver
of anything in crypto.
You know, where is the stablecoin demand
coming from?
Where is most stablecoins being used? We
talk a lot about institutions and
institutions are very excited about
stablecoins. But where are most
stablecoins being used? In emerging
markets, right? Exactly. Um Those
emerging markets, obviously there are
not institutions in those emerging
markets. Um
the the the overall
picture of crypto is that crypto is
really a bottoms-up technology.
It's not a top-down technology. It's not
that, oh, you know, the government and
the businesses and the Fortune 500
companies, they're all going to adopt
crypto and that's why crypto's going to
be big. No, no, no, no.
It's almost never how disruptive
technologies work.
Disruptive technologies get adopted from
the bottoms-up. Right? You think about
the iPhone? The iPhone was not adopted
by businesses, it was adopted by
individuals. Adopted by people. The
reality is that
you will be surprised
how much the world changes when you
allow people to see the value in these
new technologies and adopt them
bottoms-up.
Right? You've probably seen these
stories of, you know, these these uh
this kind of stuff is exactly how new
technologies get adopted.
People see the vision, they get excited,
and they say, "You know what? I'm going
to try it." Same thing they did with,
you know, what how why is it that 15% of
Americans own crypto? Everyone says,
"Oh, crypto's so hard to use, so scary,
so this or that." And yet 15% of
Americans own it.
This is because people see
the vision of the future
and they want to pull it into the
present. It's always how it's been done.
Bottoms-up, not top-down.
That's a part of it. A part A big part
is people were promised that they're
going to get generational wealth.
Mhm.
It's true. And
>> Is that still true?
It's I mean, look, there is no story
that's going to result in people making,
you know, easy overnight money.
Mhm.
>> Anything that results in easy overnight
money, if quickly won, is quickly lost.
Same thing happened in the dot-com
bubble.
Right? People thought like, "Oh my god,
the internet's going to change
everything. Great, I should buy every
single stock and lever up and, you know,
take a mortgage on my house and go buy
uh tech stocks." And they got killed.
Everybody who did that ultimately got
punished. But in the long run, if you
held those companies,
every single one of them
was a huge returner even relative to the
high of the dot-com bubble.
Um
And so the same thing I think is true in
crypto is that, look, if you buy if you
bought Bitcoin at 120
and you're down to 70, you're like,
"Man, this crypto stuff. Total
scam. This space is, you know, full of
lies. Nothing ever really happens in
this space." And yet, if you hold that
for 10 years,
I'm going to guess that you are going to
make a lot of money.
That's true for a Bitcoin. What about
other altcoins? Solana, Ethereum. Now,
people are even worried about Ethereum.
Yeah, I mean, they should be. Um for
everything besides Bitcoin, there's
still a lot of game to be played.
I think the best smart contract platform
is going to be worth a lot more in 10
years. But is it going to be Ethereum?
Is it going to be Solana? Is it going to
be something else?
The reality is that you don't get any
guarantees
in the world of technology competition.
Right? Just because you were there
first, you might be the IBM. You might
be the first one to go when the next
technology trend arrives. So, IBM at one
point was the most valuable company in
the world. Now, you can barely see them
on the top 50.
So, um nobody is given the right
independent of execution to stay on top.
You have to earn it. The internet era,
where you hold the good company, the
right company, you're going to make it,
right? But in crypto, we have equity and
token. So, people have this hard time to
understand these the difference between
these two, and where does value go? For
example, um
Intercontinental Exchange, you know,
invested in OKX at 25 billion valuation,
but OKX has OKB. Now,
Mhm. where does the value go? If you
look at ICE, so my understanding was
that that deal was an investment of 200
million dollars.
Yes.
200 million dollars means that they
bought less than 1% of OKX.
And ICE is worth over 100 billion.
So, ICE investing 200 million at a 100
billion-dollar company, that means they
invested 20 basis points of their
company into OKX.
If that was a good investment, I don't
even know if it would show up in the ICE
stock price, right? Let's say they 5x
their investment.
That means that they have 800 million
dollars of profits. That means the
valuation of ICE should go up
.8%.
Could you even tell on a given day if
ICE went up because of its investment in
OKX? I don't know.
>> OKB went up a lot.
OKB went up a lot because OKB is worth a
lot less than than ICE is worth. Um
like OKB is like a, you know, I don't
know, a billion-dollar token or
something like that, whereas ICE is
worth 100 billion plus. Um so, all that
is to say, there's a you you have to
understand the relative scale of what
you're buying if you're buying an equity
versus you're buying a token. Um
Now, that said, it's important to also
remember the sense of scale, okay? Um
The entire crypto market, like just
crypto assets, is over I think it's on
the order of like 2.5 trillion today.
Okay? Um if you own a loan
is over $200 billion.
If you look at the crypto companies that
are public,
biggest is Coinbase. Coinbase is about
50 billion.
Uh then you get to Circle. Circle's
like, you know, 19, 20. Uh and then it
it drops off pretty readily from there,
right? So, you add all those together,
maybe you get something like 100 billion
in total value.
Which means that
all of the stock market for crypto
is worth less than half of Ethereum.
Right? The crypto native market is way
bigger
than the crypto stock market, at least
today.
Um now, that it's possible that changes
at some point in the future, but it has
not changed anytime in recent memory,
and I don't think it's that likely to
change. And that's just Ethereum, saying
nothing of Solana and all the other
assets that are out there that follow
Ethereum. So, the the crypto market is
mostly the crypto asset market. The
stock market is great,
but it's a sideshow right now to where
the real trading volume, liquidity, and
the the overall mass of value in the
crypto industry is. It's still mostly in
the token market. So, it's important not
to forget that.
You don't need to say that investing in
stocks is bad.
Um no, I don't think that's going to
change.
I think that the majority of value will
continue to be in crypto assets, not in
crypto stocks. When I'm explaining what
tokens are to people that are not
familiar with crypto, I use the IPO ICO
analogy, right? It's just that you're
holding a piece of the company, but
people are more used to the concept of
equity. They're like, well, aren't you
just talking about equity now? But now
there's equity and token, and you're
trying to explain token
by telling me it's equity. Like, you
know, it's a little confusing sometimes.
>> Mhm.
So, I think there are tokens that
represent different things.
So,
>> Right.
like, for example, you can buy a stock
that's a holding company that just
includes a bunch of gold in it.
Um
Now, I don't know why you'd do that.
That's not very tax efficient, but let's
say you did that.
Uh that stock is a stock, but it's not
really an equity.
Technically, it's an equity, but it
really represents gold. It represents a
commodity, right? So, the
is the fact that it's a stock
change anything? Well, not really. A
stock is just like a wrapper for an
underlying asset. What's the underlying
asset? So, for another thing that you
can see is uh REITs, right? So, a REIT
is a real estate trust. Uh real estate
investment trust. So, if you were to buy
a REIT, now again, let's assume that
it's in the stock market.
Often times REITs are are are uh listed
differently, but let's say it's in the
stock market, okay? So, you buy a REIT.
A REIT is basically just a bunch of
apartment complexes in different parts
of the country.
You bought a stock.
But really, the stock represents real
estate. So, you kind of bought real
estate.
But like that the underlying exposure is
real estate, but the thing you bought is
a stock. So, you might think like, oh,
well, I have exposure to the stock
market. I have exposure to, you know,
what the cash flows are. Well, I mean,
you kind of do, but the main thing you
have exposure to is real estate, right?
It's the underlying asset. So, in the
same way, a token is just a handle
on an asset, the same way that a stock
is a handle on an asset. But the
question is, what is the handle
connected to?
Is it connected to a commodity, like
gold? Is it connected to uh you know, a
real asset, like real estate? Or is it
connected to a company that has cash
flows and dividends and all this other
stuff? Then okay, well, that that's what
we normally think of as an equity, is a
share in a business, right? But not
every equity represents a share in a
business.
So, what does a token represent? The
answer is, show me the network and I'll
tell you.
For Bitcoin,
what does Bitcoin represent, right? Does
it give you cash flows in anything? No,
there's no cash flows in Bitcoin.
It just gives you a commodity. Bitcoin's
a commodity.
So, okay, now I have Ether.
What does Ether represent? Well, Ether
is a little more complicated, right?
It's got cash flows because Ether gets
burned. There's revenues for the chain.
It's also a commodity because you use
Ether to pay for gas. So, it's kind of
the oil of Ethereum. Um it's also
currency, right? Things get priced in
Ether on top of Ethereum. Not a lot of
things anymore, but there's still some
things that get priced in in Ether.
Um so, it's kind of a It's hard to
describe exactly what it is. Now, if you
look at something like Hyperliquid,
okay, Hyperliquid, this really looks
more like a share in a business, right?
The business is decentralized exchange,
and you get a piece of the profits if
you own some of Hype token, right? Same
thing with Uniswap, right? If you you
own Uniswap, you get a piece of the fees
if you own some UNI token. So, different
tokens represent different things.
Uh if on the other hand you invest into,
you know, Digix uh or um USDG, right?
Okay, well, now you're investing into
gold. It's a token,
but the token what is the token a handle
on? It's a handle on a real asset or a
commodity, and so therefore, you're
really investing in the gold even though
it's a token. So, token is just a
wrapper.
It doesn't necessarily imply what the
underlying valuable asset is or does.
So beautifully said. Um can I
can I think of it this way?
A company should not IPO and also have a
token.
Uh Cuz that's very confusing.
Maybe. Maybe, maybe not. Um
one can imagine, for example, let's say
that Polymarket IPOs.
Okay?
>> Mhm.
Uh what are they IPOing? They also have
a token. What are they IPOing? Well, you
can imagine that they IPO their US
regulated business,
which is off-chain,
but then they have a token that
represents their off-chain, or sorry,
their on-chain offshore business, which
is not available to Americans. Right?
So, Americans can trade on the US
regulated exchange, which has CFTC
license, it's surveilled, you know, like
you can't You have to KYC, you have to
do all this stuff. Uh and the way you
get exposure to that is you buy
Polymarket on the stock market.
But if you want exposure to the
off-chain Polymarket, you go buy the
token.
And that thing is that thing is on the
blockchain, it's decentralized, you
know, it's permissionless.
Um so, I can imagine a world where
there's actually a very coherent way to
divide
uh into an off-chain business, quote
unquote,
and an on-chain business, quote unquote.
But most things
I would not categorize that way.
I think most things, if you have both
equity and a token, you're probably
double-dipping or you're doing something
very confusing.
And also, you know, Nasdaq announced a
partnership with Kraken to enable 24/7
um tokenized stock trading. So, then you
remove the barrier of entry. Now
everybody can, well, hopefully, invest
in US stock. Right, not everybody yet,
but that's the dream, right?
People
>> Well, that's not their dream. That might
be our dream, but that's not the
Nasdaq's dream. The Nasdaq is not trying
to get, you know, Chinese people to be
able to trade US stocks.
Um so, we might think that that's a
valuable thing, but I don't think the
Nasdaq agrees with this.
Right. But okay, let's not talk about
like the legislation and the law, but
it's removing the barrier of entry, and
then, you know, they're promising that
it's going to happen 20 27, and now, you
know, all the token holders have the
same rights as traditional investors.
So, in that case,
>> So,
>> Okay. i- if you're talking about
tokenized stocks,
Mhm. the expectation for tokenized
stocks is that you are KYCing
on the exchange. They know who you are.
You can buy fractional shares, which
right now, you go to stock market, you
can't buy fractional shares on a lot of
platforms.
>> Um like you can on Robinhood, but you
can't on a lot of other platforms. Um
So, you can buy fractional shares. You
can trade them 24/7.
The end.
That's it. It's not, okay, anybody can
trade, anybody You don't have to KYC,
you know, you can take your things
off-chain and go do whatever crazy thing
you want with it. Uh it's like, no, no,
no, no. All it is is 24/7 and
fractionalized.
That's they give you.
>> For now.
>> So, if you want Well, there's no there's
not even a proposal to do anything more
than that because it's not compatible
with securities laws. Mhm. If you want
like Hyperliquid level
insanity,
that's not going to happen because, you
know, the NYSE or the Nasdaq partners up
with somebody to do tokenization.
Tokenization does not give you that
property. So, what what is more
subversive
is the thing that we see on crypto every
day, which is this global permissionless
unstoppable financial market.
It's the, you know, internet capital
markets as we often call them. Uh that
thing
is not going to happen because the
Nasdaq wants it to. It's going to happen
because the world wants it to.
Does it start with crypto exchanges
becoming, you know, universal everything
exchange? That is one part of the path,
but I I think DeFi also has a large role
to play. And increasingly, what you see
is that a lot of the exchanges are
leaning more and more on DeFi and
non-custodial
uh applications in order to allow their
customers to be able to do whatever they
want to do.
So, it's like, okay, well, if you can't
do it on our platform,
stay on our wallet and do it from from,
you know, our
uh ecosystem. Did you grow up in a very
wealthy family?
No.
I grew up in a
a pretty middle class family. I mean,
when when my parents uh when I was born,
we lived in a very small apartment. My
parents had just emigrated from Pakistan
to the US.
Uh I was born in Texas. So, you know, we
lived
very, you know, like my my parents were
college students uh trying to make ends
meet as immigrants.
Um but I I mostly grew up middle class.
If you could go back, what would you say
to, you know,
yourself when you just started?
What are some advice you would give
yourself? So, one, um
I would say,
choose the path that makes you stronger.
Um
I would tell myself
that the most important skill in life is
saying no to things.
Oh, yes.
Assuming that
the longer that you say no, and the
longer that you hold on to your
opportunities
something amazing will come along.
And if you say yes too early, you risk
losing the really big opportunity that's
waiting for you.
Um
the last thing I would say is um
spend less time
uh trying to please other people
and more time building relationships
and taking care of them. I love that. I
think um everyone's going to find it
very insightful and I hope you come back
and share more cuz this is amazing.
>> This was a lot of fun. I appreciate you
having me on, Mike.